Guide to the Margaret S. Mahler Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1924-1984; Series III; 16 linear feet (36 boxes)
  - Articles, Reviews, Scientific Papers: Published
    - "Thoughts About Development and Individuation," Psychoanalytic Study of the Child, 18:307-324. (Box 65, Folder 1152)
    - (Furer, M. & Mahler, M.) "Certain Aspects of the Separation-Individuation Phase," Psychoanalytic Quarterly, 32:1-14., 1963 (Box 65, Folder 1153)
    - Foreword: "Project on Child Psychosis," Reiss-Davis Clinic Bulletin, 1964 (Box 66, Folder 1154)
    - "On Early Infantile Psychosis: The Symbiotic and Autistic Syndromes," Journal of the American Academyof Child psychiatry, 4:554-568., 1965 (Box 66, Folder 1155)
    - "On the Significance of the Normal Separation-Individuation Phase: With Reference to Research in Symbiotic Child Psychosis," Drives, Affects, Behavior, ed. M. Schur. (New York: International Universities Press)., 1965 (Box 66, Folder 1156)
    - (LaPerriere, K. & Mahler, M.) "Mother-Child Interaction During Separation-Individuation," Psychoanalytic Quarterly, 34:483-498., 1965 (Box 66, Folder 1157)
    - "Childhood Schizophrenia," Panel Discussion. Bulletin of the Association for Psychoanalytic Medicine, 5:35-42., 1966 (Box 66, Folder 1158)
    - "Notes of the Development of Basic Moods: The Depressive Affect," Psychoanalysis: A GeneralPsychology—Essays in Honor of Heinz Hartmann, ed. R.M. Lowenstein, L. M. Newman, M. Schur, & A.J. Solnit. (New York: International Universities Press)., 1966 (Box 66, Folder 1159)
    - "Some Preliminary Notes on the Development of Basic Moods, Including Depression," Canadian, Psychiatric Association Journal, suppl. 2:250-258., 1966 (Box 66, Folder 1160)
    - (Furer, M. &Mahler, M.) "Development of Symbiosis, Symbiotic Psychosis and the Nature of Separation Anxiety—Remarks on Weiland's Paper," International Journal of Psycho-Analysis, 1966 (Box 66, Folder 1161)
    - "Development of 'Defense' From Biological and Symbiotic Precursors: Adaptive and Maladaptive Aspects," In: "Panel on Development and Metapsychology of the Defense Organization of the Ego", reported by R.S. Wallerstein. Journalof the American Psychoanalytic Association, 15:130-149., 1967 (Box 66, Folder 1162)
    - "Characterological Aspects of Marital Interactions," discussion. Psychoanalytic Forum, 2:14-15., 1967 (Box 66, Folder 1163)
    - "On Human Symbiosis and the Vicissitudes of Individuation," Journal of the American Psychoanalytic Association, 15:740-763., 1967 (Box 66, Folder 1164)
    - "Child Development and the Curriculum," Journal of the American Psychoanalytic Association, 15:876-886., 1967 (Box 66, Folder 1165)
    - Über Psychose and Schizophrenie im Kindesalter, Autische und Symbiotische Frühkindlische Psychosen, Psyche, 21:895-914., 1967 (Box 66, Folder 1166)
    - "A Study of How the Child Separates from the Mother," Mental Health Program Reports, prepared by Herbert Yahraes. National Institute of Mental Health., 1967 (Box 66, Folder 1167)
    - Comment of Dr. Löfgren's Paper: "Castration Anxiety and the Body Ego," presented before the International Psycho-Analytical Congress, Copenhagen. International Journal of Psychoanalysis, 49:410-412., 1968 (Box 66, Folder 1168)
    - "The Self Limitations of Lauretta Bender's Biological Theory," International Journal of Psychiatry, 5:230-233., 1968 (Box 66, Folder 1169)
    - (McDevitt, J. &Mahler, M.) "Observations on Adaptation and Defense In StatuNascendi: Developmental Precursors in the First Two Years of Life," Psychoanalytic Quarterly, 37:1-21., 1968 (Box 66, Folder 1170)
    - (Pine, F.; Bergman, A.; & Mahler, M.) "The Mother's Reaction to Her Toddler's Drive for Individuation," Parenthood, E. J. Anthony & T. Benedek, eds. (Boston: Little & Brown), 1969 (Box 67, Folder 1171)
    - "Perturbances of Symbiosis and Individuation in the Development of the Psychotic Ego," Excerpta Medica Monograph, International Congress Series, 194: 188-195, 1969 (Box 67, Folder 1172)
    - "Loss of Love Objects as Intrapsychic Process," Journal of the American Psychiatric Association Abstract, 1969 (Box 67, Folder 1173)
    - "Autismo y symbiosis: dos trastornos extremos de la identidad," Revista de Psicoanalisis, suppl. 26: 201-216, 1969 (Box 67, Folder 1174)
    - "A Study of the Separation-Individuation Process and its Possible Application to Borderline Phenomena in the Psychoanalytic Situation," Psychoanalytic Study of the Child, 26: 403-424, 1971 (Box 67, Folder 1175)
    - Acceptance of the Frieda Fromm- Reichmann Award Techniques of Therapy, J. H. Wasserman, ed., Ch. 13; NY, Grune and Stratton, 1971 (Box 67, Folder 1176)
    - "Infant Observation and Longitudinal Study: Implications for Mental Health and Primary Prevention of Mental Disorders in High Risk Situations," Journal of the American Academy of Child Psychiatry, 1971 (Box 67, Folder 1177)
    - (with Furer, M.) Child "Psychosis: A Theoretical Statement and its Implications," Journal of Autism andChildhood Schizophrenia, 213: 213-218, 1972 (Box 67, Folder 1178)
    - "Rapprochment Subphase of the Separation-Individuation Process," Psychoanalytic Quarterly, 41:487-506, 1972 (Box 67, Folder 1179)
    - "On the First Three Subphases of the Separation-Individuation Process," International Journal of Psycho-Analysis, 53: 333-338, 1972 (Box 67, Folder 1180)
    - "On the First Three Subphases of the Separation-Individuation Process," Mental Health Digest, 5: 7-10, 1973 (Box 67, Folder 1181)
    - "On the First Three Subphases of the Separation-Individuation Process," Psychoanalysis and Contemporary Science, 3: 295-306, 1974 (Box 67, Folder 1182)
    - "Symbiosis and Individuation: The Psychological Birth of the Human Infant," Psychoanalytic Study of the Child, 29: 89-106, 1974 (Box 67, Folder 1183)
    - Discussion of Bernard L. Pacella's Paper: "Early Ego Development and the Deja Vu," Journal of the American Psychoanalytic Association, 23: 322-326, 1975 (Box 67, Folder 1184)
    - Discussion of: "Healthy Parental Influences on the Earliest Development of Masculinity in Baby Boys," by Robert Stoller, M.D. Psychoanalytic Forum, 5: 97-98, 1975 (Box 67, Folder 1185)
    - "On the Current Status of Infantile Psychosis," Journal of the American Psychoanalytic Association, 23: 327-333, 1975 (Box 67, Folder 1186)
    - "Symbiose and Individuation: Die Psychische Geburt des Menschenkindes," Psyche, 29: 609-625, 1975 (Box 67, Folder 1187)
    - "Longitudinal Study of the Treatment of a Psychotic Child with the Tripartite Design," Journal of the Philadelphia Association for Psychoanalysis, III: 21-42, 1976 (Box 67, Folder 1188)
    - "Developmental Aspects in the Assessment of Narcissistic and So-called Borderline Personalities," Borderline Personality Disorders, Peter Hartocollis, ed.; NY, International Universities Press, 1977 (Box 67, Folder 1189)
    - Foreword to: Oneness and Separateness, by Lois J. Kaplan; NY, Simon and Schuster, 1978 (Box 67, Folder 1190)
    - Epilogue: "The Child In His Family," vol. 4, Vulnerable Children, E. James Anthony, et. al., eds., 1978 (Box 67, Folder 1191)
    - Foreword to: Ego Psychology II, Psychoanalytic Developmental Psychology, Gertrude and Reuben Blanck, 1979 (Box 67, Folder 1192)
    - "Die Subphase der Wiederannäherung in Loslösungsund Individuationsprozeß," Wegezum Menschen, 5/6: 202-215, 1979 (Box 67, Folder 1193)
    - (with McDevitt, J. B.) "Object Constancy, Individuality, and Internalization," The Course of Life: Psychoanalytic Contributions Toward Understanding Personality Development vol. 1- Infancy and Early Childhood National Institute of Mental Health, 1980 (Box 68, Folder 1194)
    - "Aggression in the Service of Separation-Individuation: Case Study of a Mother-Daughter Relationship," Psychoanalytic Quarterly, 50: 625-638, 1981 (Box 68, Folder 1195)
    - "The Meaning of Early Developmental Research as Related to the Study of Separation-Individuation," Frontiers in Infant, Psychiatry, J. D. Call, et. al., eds., [1981] (Box 68, Folder 1196)
    - (with McDevitt, J. B.) "Some Thoughts on the Emergence of the Sense of Self, with Particular Emphasis on the Body Self," Journal of the American Psychoanalytic Association, 50: 827-848, 1982 (Box 68, Folder 1197)
    - Un estudio del proceso de separacion-individuación y su posible aplicación a los fenomenos fronterizos en la situacion psicoanalitica, Psicoanalisis, 4: 94-116, 1982 (Box 68, Folder 1198)
    - Graduation Address Postgraduate Center for Mental Health Dynamic Psychotherapy, the Journal of the Postgraduate Center for Mental Health, 2: 68-69, 1983 (Box 68, Folder 1199)
  - Articles, Reviews, Scientific Papers: Unpublished
    - Review of: The Psychoanalytic Study of the Child, vol. 2; NY, International Universities Press; for, 1946 (Box 68, Folder 1200)
    - Grune and Stratton Book, Circa 1956-1957 (Box 68, Folder 1201)
    - Definitions for: The Dictionary of Behavioral Science, Benjamin Wolman, M.D., ed., Circa 1972 (Box 68, Folder 1202)
    - "Notes on Reversibility of Later Pathology With Special Reference to Studies On Separation-Individuation," International Review of Psychoanalysis, Circa 1974 (Box 68, Folder 1203)
    - Abstract: "On the Current State of Infantile Neurosis," for: Psychiatry Digest, 1975 (Box 68, Folder 1204)
  - Articles, Reviews, Scientific Papers: Unidentified
    - "Clinical Contributions to the Question of Severe Intellectual Restriction,", undated (Box 68, Folder 1205)
    - Definition of Autism, for Glossary of Fine and Moore, undated (Box 68, Folder 1206)
    - Essay on Anna Freud's Book: Normalityand Pathology in Childhood, Assesment of Development, undated (Box 68, Folder 1207)
    - Foreword to: Dependence in Man: A Psychoanalytic Study, undated (Box 68, Folder 1208)
    - "Reaction of Mothers to the Child's Press for Individuation.", undated (Box 68, Folder 1209)
  - Articles, Reviews, Scientific Papers: Unpublished
    - "Severe Emotional Disturbances in Childhood Psychoses in Children," by Margaret S. Mahler, M.D., Manuel Furer, M.D., and Calvin Settlage, M.D., undated (Box 68, Folder 1210)
    - "Therapeutic Aspects in Educational Emergency Situations.", undated (Box 68, Folder 1211)
    - "Treatment of the Symbiotic Psychotic Child within the Mother-Child-Therapist Triad.", undated (Box 68, Folder 1212)
    - "Die Communication Zwischen Neugeborenem and Mutter…", undated (Box 68, Folder 1213)
    - "In dem Aufsatz: die Handhabung der Traumdeutung…", undated (Box 68, Folder 1214)
  - Manuscripts: Published
    - On Human Symbiosis and the Vicissitudes of Individuation
      - Acknowledgements, 1968 (Box 69, Folder 1215)
      - Table of Contents, 1968 (Box 69, Folder 1216)
      - Introduction, 1968 (Box 69, Folder 1217)
      - Chapter II: The Symbiosis Theory of Infantile Psychosis, 1968 (Box 69, Folder 1218-1221)
      - Chapter III: Diagnostic Considerations, 1968 (Box 69, Folder 1222)
      - Chapter IV: Clinical Cases of Child Psychosis, 1968 (Box 69, Folder 1223-1226)
      - Chapter V: Prototypes of Mother-Child Interaction, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 1227)
      - Chapter V: Theory, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 1228)
      - Chapter V: Theory, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 1229-1130)
      - Chapter VII: Conclusions, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 1231)
      - References, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 1232)
      - Bibliographical Notes, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 1233)
      - Reviews, 1968-1970 (Box 70, Folder 1234)
      - Dust Jacket, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 1235)
      - Notes, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 1236)
    - The Psychological Birth of the Human Infant
      - Table of Contents, Outline, 1970,1973, undated (Box 70, Folder 1237)
      - Preface, 1972, 1973, undated (Box 70, Folder 1238)
      - Acknowledgments, undated (Box 70, Folder 1239)
      - Introduction, 1972, 1973, undated (Box 70, Folder 1240)
      - Introduction and Historical Review, undated (Box 70, Folder 1241)
      - Section I, Chapter 1 Introduction and Historical Background, 1970 Nov, 1971 October (Box 71, Folder 1242)
      - Section I, Chapter 1 Background, Overview, 1972 Sep, 1973 February (Box 71, Folder 1243)
      - Section I, Chapter 1 Untitled, undated (Box 71, Folder 1244)
      - Section I, Chapter 2 Untitled, undated (Box 71, Folder 1245)
      - Section I, Chapter 2 Theory, 1972 September (Box 71, Folder 1246)
      - Section I, Chapters 1 and 2, Insert, 1973 (Box 71, Folder 1247)
      - Section II, Chapter 1 Methodological Considerations, 1972 March (Box 71, Folder 1248)
      - Section II, Chapter 2 Methodological Considerations, 1971 Jan, 1971 April (Box 71, Folder 1249-1250)
      - Section II, Chapter 2 Methodological Considerations, 1972 December (Box 72, Folder 1251)
      - Section II, Chapter 3 Separation-Individuation Phase: Its Forerunners and Its Subphases, 1971 December (Box 72, Folder 1252)
      - Section II, Insert, undated (Box 72, Folder 1253)
      - Section II, Chapters 1-5, 1973 (Box 72, Folder 1254)
        General
        1. Forerunners of the Separation -Individuation Process
        2. Differentiation and the Development of the Body Image
        3. The Practicing Subphase
      - Section II, Chapters 1-5, 1973 (Box 72, Folder 1255)
        4. The Subphase of Rapprochment
        5. The Fourth Subphase: The Gradual Attainment of Libidinal Object Constancy
      - Section II, Chapters 4-8, undated (Box 72, Folder 1256)
        4. Forerunners of the Separation-Individuation Process
        5. Differentiation and the Development of the Body Image
      - Section II, Chapters 4-8, undated (Box 72, Folder 1257)
        7. The Subphase of Rapprochment
        8. The Fourth Subphase: Consolidation of Individuation and Emotional Object Constancy
      - Section III, Chapter 1 The Separation-Individuation Phase, Its Forerunners and Its Subphases, 1972 Jan, Nov, Dec, 1973 Apr, undated (Box 72, Folder 1258-1259)
      - Section III, Chapter 1 Differentiation (Box 72, Folder 1260)
      - Section III, Chapter 2 Untitled, undated (Box 72, Folder 1261)
      - Section III, Chapters 1, 2, 1971 Dec, 1972 January (Box 73, Folder 1262)
        1. Separation-Individuation Phase, Its Forerunners and Its Subphases
        2. Differentiation
      - Section III, Chapter 3 Normal Autistic and Normal Symbiotic Phases, 1972 April (Box 73, Folder 1263)
      - Section III, Chapter 3 The Subphase of Rapprochment, insert, 1972 November (Box 73, Folder 1264)
      - Section III, Chapter 3 Practicing Subphase, 1973 April (Box 73, Folder 1265)
      - Section III, Chapter 4 Untitled, 1972 Nov, 1973 February (Box 73, Folder 1266)
      - Section III, Chapter 4 Untitled, undated (Box 73, Folder 1267)
      - Section III, Chapter 4 Subphase of Rapprochment, 1973 Feb, April (Box 73, Folder 1268)
      - Section III, Chapter 4 The Subphase of Rapprochment-"Copy Edited by Mr. Collins", 1973 April (Box 73, Folder 1269)
      - Section III, Chapter 5 The Fourth Phase: Gradual Attainment of Libidinal Object Constancy, undated (Box 73, Folder 1270)
      - Section III, Chapters 3, 4, 1972 Jan, undated (Box 74, Folder 1271)
        3. The Subphase of Rapprochment
        4. Untitled
      - Section III, Chapters 2, 4, undated (Box 74, Folder 1272)
        4. Subphase of Rapprochment
      - Section III, Chapters 4, 5, undated (Box 74, Folder 1273)
        4. The Subphases of Rapprochment
        5. The Fourth Subphase: Gradual Attainment of Libidinal Object Constancy
      - Section III, Chapters 1-5, 1973 March (Box 74, Folder 1274)
        1. Separation-Individuation Phase…
        5. The Fourth Subphase…
      - Section III, Chapters 2, 3, 4, 1973 March (Box 74, Folder 1275)
        1. Differentiation
        2. The Practicing Subphase
        3. Subphase of Rapprochment
      - Section III, Chapters 1-5, 1973 April (Box 74, Folder 1276)
        1. Forerunners of Separation-Individuation
        2. Differentiation…
      - Section III, Chapters 1-5 Incomplete, 1971 December-1972 January (Box 74, Folder 1277-1279)
      - Section III, Chapter 1 Introduction, undated (Box 75, Folder 1280)
      - Section III, Chapter 2 Peter, Teddy, Susan, Heather, 1969 Oct, 1972 January (Box 75, Folder 1281)
      - Section III, Chapter 2 Peter, Susan, Donna, Sam, 1972 January (Box 75, Folder 1282)
      - Section III, Chapter 2 Peter, Donna, Susan, undated (Box 75, Folder 1283)
      - Section III, Chapter 2 Teddy, 1972 June (Box 75, Folder 1284)
      - Section III, Chapter 3 Sam, Teddy, Susan, 1972 Jan, Feb, March (Box 75, Folder 1285)
      - Section III, Chapter 3 Donna, Sam, Teddy, Susan, 1972 Feb, March (Box 75, Folder 1286)
      - Section III, Chapter 3 Peter, Susan, 1972 Feb, undated (Box 75, Folder 1287)
      - Section III, Chapter 3 Edited by Anni Bergman Peter, Donna, Sam, Teddy, Susan, 1972 Feb, March (Box 75, Folder 1288)
      - Section III, Chapter 4 Teddy, undated (Box 75, Folder 1289)
      - Section III, Chapter 5 Peter, Donna, Susan, Teddy, 1972 January-June (Box 76, Folder 1290)
      - Section III, Chapter 5 Sam, Teddy, undated (Box 76, Folder 1291)
      - Section III, Chapters 5, 7 Teddy, Sam, undated (Box 76, Folder 1292)
      - Section III, Chapters 6, 7 The Fourth Subphase Susan, Peter, Donna, Teddy, Sam, 1972 January-September (Box 76, Folder 1293)
      - Section III, Chapter 7 Donna, Susan, Teddy, Sam, 1973 April (Box 76, Folder 1294)
      - Section III, Chapter 7 Susan, 1972 August (Box 76, Folder 1295)
      - Section III, Chapter 7 Donna, 1972 August (Box 76, Folder 1296)
      - Section III, Chapter 7 Peter, 1972 Sep, 1973 Jan, Apr, 1974 March (Box 76, Folder 1297)
      - Section III, Chapter 7 Teddy, Sam, 1972 August (Box 76, Folder 1298)
      - Section III, Chapter 9 Peter, Donna, Susan, Teddy, Sam, 1972 August (Box 77, Folder 1299)
      - Section III, Chapter 9 Peter, Donna, Susan, undated (Box 77, Folder 1300)
      - Section III, Chapter 9 Peter/Bruce, 1972 Aug, 1974 Mar, undated (Box 77, Folder 1301)
      - Section III, Chapter 10 Donna, undated (Box 77, Folder 1302)
      - Section III, Chapter 11 Susan, 1974 March (Box 77, Folder 1303)
      - Section III, Chapter 12 Teddy, undated (Box 77, Folder 1304)
      - Section III, Chapter 13 Roy/Sara, undated (Box 77, Folder 1305)
      - Section III, Chapters 1-5, undated (Box 77, Folder 1306)
        1. Peter
        2. Donna
        3. Susan
        4. Teddy
        5. Sam
      - Section III, Chapters 1-5, Incomplete, 1974 April (Box 78, Folder 1307)
        1. Bruce
        2. Marta
        3. Wendy
        5. Roy (not included)
      - Section III, Chapters 9-13, undated (Box 78, Folder 1308)
        9. Peter
        10. Donna
        11. Susan
        12. Teddy
        13. Sam
      - Section III, Chapters 11-13, undated (Box 78, Folder 1309)
        11. Susan/Wendy
        13. Sam/Roy
      - Section III, Chapters 10-13, 1974 April (Box 78, Folder 1310)
      - Section III, Chapter Unidentified Teddy, Sam, 1972 January (Box 78, Folder 1311)
      - Section III, Chapter Unidentified Bruce, undated (Box 78, Folder 1312)
      - Section III, Chapter Unidentified Sam, undated (Box 78, Folder 1313)
      - Section III, Chapter Unidentified Donna, 1974 March (Box 78, Folder 1314)
      - Section III, Chapter Unidentified, undated (Box 78, Folder 1315)
      - Section IV, Chapter 1 Concluding Section, 1973 Nov, undated (Box 79, Folder 1316)
      - Section IV, Chapter 1 Peter, 1973, Mar, April (Box 79, Folder 1317)
      - Section IV, Chapter 1 Sam, undated (Box 79, Folder 1318)
      - Section IV, Chapter 1 Donna, Susan, Teddy, Sam, undated (Box 79, Folder 1319)
      - Section IV, Chapter 2 Donna, 1972 Feb, April (Box 79, Folder 1320)
      - Section IV, Chapter 2 Donna, undated (Box 79, Folder 1321)
      - Section IV, Chapter 3 Susan, 1973 Apr, Nov, undated (Box 79, Folder 1322)
      - Section IV, Chapter 4 Teddy, 1973 Apr, undated (Box 79, Folder 1323)
      - Section IV, Chapter 5 Sam, undated (Box 79, Folder 1324)
      - Section IV, Chapter 6 Conclusions, 1973 April (Box 79, Folder 1325)
      - Section IV, Chapters 1-6, 1973 Apr, undated (Box 80, Folder 1326)
        6. Conclusion
      - Section IV, Chapters 1-6, 1973 April (Box 80, Folder 1327)
        6. Conclusions
      - Section IV, Chapter 11 Applications: Some Developmental Points of Vulnerability to Psychopathology, 1971 November (Box 80, Folder 1328)
      - Section IV, Chapter 12 Applications: Some Phenomena Relevant to the Psychoanalysis of Adults, undated (Box 80, Folder 1329)
      - Section IV, Chapter 13 Introduction, undated (Box 80, Folder 1330)
      - Section IV, Chapter 13 Introduction, 1973 Dec, undated (Box 80, Folder 1331)
      - Section IV, Chapter 14 Variations and Vicissitudes within the Subphases of Separation-Individuation with Special Reference to Differentiation, undated (Box 80, Folder 1332)
      - Section IV, Chapter 14 On the Development of Basic Moods and Its Relation to Gender Identity, 1974 February (Box 80, Folder 1333)
      - Section IV, Chapter 15 Epigenesis of Subphase-specific Separation Anxiety…, undated (Box 80, Folder 1334)
      - Section IV, Chapter 16 Roots of Self-Identity and their Indices in Behavior…, undated (Box 81, Folder 1335)
      - Section IV, Chapter 17 Some Concluding Remarks about the Rapprochment Crisis and its…, undated (Box 81, Folder 1336)
      - Section IV, Chapters 14-17, undated (Box 81, Folder 1337-1340)
        14. Variations and Vicissitudes of Differentiation
        15. Epigenesis of Subphase-Specific Separation Anxiety
        16. Reflections on Core-Identity and Self…
        17. Concluding Remarks…
      - Section IV, Chapter Unidentified, undated (Box 81, Folder 1341)
      - Section IV, Conclusions, 1973 March-1974 Nov, 1973 March-April (Box 81, Folder 1342-1343)
      - Section V, Chapter 12 Selected Aspects of the Psychoanalytic Literature, undated (Box 81, Folder 1344)
      - Appendix A, undated (Box 81, Folder 1345)
      - Appendix C, 1971 January (Box 81, Folder 1346)
      - Appendix, undated (Box 82, Folder 1347-1348)
        I. The Available Data
        II. A Research Rationale
        III. Some Research Strategies
      - Subject Index, undated (Box 82, Folder 1349)
      - Author Index, undated (Box 82, Folder 1350)
      - Section I, Preface; Section III, Chapters 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 1973 February (Box 82, Folder 1351)
      - Section I, Chapters 1, 2; Section III, Chapters 1, 2, 1973 March 21 (Box 82, Folder 1352)
      - Section I, Chapters 1, 2, 3 Mastercopy, 1973 April (Box 82, Folder 1353)
      - Section II, Chapters 1, 2, 3 Mastercopy, 1973 April (Box 83, Folder 1354-1355)
      - Section II, Chapters 1-5 Mastercopy, undated (Box 83, Folder 1356-1357)
      - Section III, Chapters 1-5, 1973 April (Box 83, Folder 1358-1359)
      - Section I, Chapters 1, 2; Section II, Chapters 1, 2, undated (Box 83, Folder 1360)
      - Section I, Chapters 1-3; Section II, Chapters 1-5, undated (Box 84, Folder 1361-1362)
      - Section III, Chapters 1-5, undated (Box 84, Folder 1363)
      - Part I, Preface, Chapters 1-3; Part II, Chapters 4-8 Green Binder, undated (Box 84, Folder 1364-1365)
      - Part I, Preface; Part II, Chapters 4-7 Green Binder, Copy 2, undated (Box 84, Folder 1366)
      - Part III, Chapters 9-13; Part IV, Chapters 14-17 Appendix, Red Binder, undated (Box 85, Folder 1367-1368)
      - Part III, Chapters 10, 12, Jan Appendix, Glossary, 1974 (Box 85, Folder 1369)
      - Fred Pine Material Preface, Chapter 1, 1970 December-1973 June (Box 85, Folder 1370)
      - Fred Pine Material Floorplans, Notes, 1970, 1973 (Box 85, Folder 1371)
      - Fred Pine Material Chapters 1-2 Bergman Approach-Distance, 1970-1973 (Box 85, Folder 1372)
      - Fred Pine Material Section IV, Applications, 1971 September (Box 85, Folder 1373)
      - Fred Pine Material Code for Marginal Notes on Source Material Chapter 3- Separation-Individuation Phase, 1971 June (Box 85, Folder 1374)